<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Penetration Testing Process</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/penetration-testing-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/penetration-testing-process/</guid>
      <description>Pentest overview Risk Management
Objective: Identify, evaluate, and mitigate risks threatening confidentiality, integrity, and availability of information systems. Strategies: Accept, transfer, avoid, or mitigate risks to maintain an acceptable risk level. Inherent Risk: Persistent risk despite implemented security controls, necessitating ongoing risk management efforts. Vulnerability Assessments
Automated Tools: Utilize scanning tools like Nessus, Qualys, OpenVAS for systematic identification of known vulnerabilities. Manual Testing: Essential for adapting attacks to target system configurations and uncovering nuanced vulnerabilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brief Intro to Hardware Attacks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/brief-intro-to-hardware-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/brief-intro-to-hardware-attacks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Bluetooth 1. What is Bluetooth?
Wireless technology standard for short-distance data transfer. Operates in the ISM band from 2.402 GHz to 2.480 GHz. Named after King Harald Bluetooth, unifying Denmark and Norway. Widely adopted for its flexibility and ease of use. 2. Bluetooth Functionality:
Pairing Process:
Discovery: Devices broadcast presence. Pairing Request: Devices find each other. Authentication: Devices authenticate using a shared secret (link key). Piconets:
Collection of connected devices (1 main, up to 7 clients).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux fundamentals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Unix 1970 release by Ken Thompson and Dennis Ritchie
Berkeley Software Distribution 1977 (copy of unix)
Richard stallman started the GNU project in 1983
Create a free Unix-like OS Linux was a personal project started in 1991 by Linus Torvalds
Create a free OS kernel Today there is more than 600 distributions of linux
Philosophy Principle Description Everything is a file All configuration files for the various services running on the Linux operating system are stored in one or more text files.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MacOS fundamentals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/macos-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/macos-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>What is macOS ? macOS is the operating system used on Apple computers. Widely used in daily home use, business management, graphical design, and arts. History Roundup
Original start to OS X: Fall 2000, public beta named Kodiak, followed by Mac OS X (10.0) Cheetah and OS X (10.1) Puma. Notable releases: OS X (10.2) Jaguar, OS X (10.3) Panther, OS X (10.4) Tiger with Intel support, OS X (10.5) Leopard with Time Machine and Boot Camp, OS X (10.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network fundamentals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/network-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/network-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>Network Terms WAN (Wide Area Network):
Definition: The Internet; a large network connecting multiple LANs. Identification: WAN-specific routing protocols like BGP and non-RFC 1918 IP schemas. LAN (Local Area Network):
Definition: Internal networks (e.g., home or office). IP Addressing: Typically RFC 1918 addresses. WLAN (Wireless Local Area Network):
Definition: Wireless variant of LAN, enabling Wi-Fi access. Security: Mainly a security designation; no fundamental difference from LAN. VPN (Virtual Private Network):</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web requests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web-requests/</guid>
      <description>HyperText Transfer Protocol (HTTP) Definition: HTTP is an application-level protocol used for accessing World Wide Web resources. It facilitates communication between a client and a server.
Components of a URL:
Scheme: Identifies the protocol (http://, https://). User Info: Optional credentials (admin:password@). Host: Resource location (hostname or IP address). Port: Separated by a colon (:80 if not specified). Path: Points to the resource being accessed (/dashboard.php) Query String: Parameters and values separated by &amp;amp; (?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>📝 : Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/</guid>
      <description>HTB Linux Fundamentals
MacOS Fundamentals
Network Fundamentals
Web Requests
Brief Intro to Hardware Attacks
Penetration Testing Process
Other CTF Write ups </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ressources</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ressources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ressources/</guid>
      <description>Reading MicroprocessorDesign</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
